<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./selector.png" type="Source" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.10" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10.xsd">
    <name>Spacy Model Selector</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        The node allows to select and load a spaCy model.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        	The node allows to select and load a spaCy model.
        	It's possible to either select one of the official spaCy models or loading a model from file.
        	Once the node is executed, the model is part of the workflow in order to allow for easy sharing of workflows.
        	However, any model that is downloaded is also cached in the location specified in the Redfield NLP Nodes preference page
        	to avoid downloading the same model more than once.
        </intro>
        <tab name="SpaCy official model">
        	<description>
        		The official spaCy models follow a naming scheme that splits the name into multiple components separated by '_'.
        		<ol>
        			<li>The first component indicates the language (e.g. <tt>en</tt>). Multi-language models use the code <tt>xx</tt>.</li>
        			<li>The second component indicates the model type and its capabilities.
        				The type <tt>core</tt> is for general-purpose pipelines that support tagging, parsing, lemmatization and named entity recognition, 
        				while the type <tt>dep</tt> only supports tagging, parsing and lemmatization.</li>
        			<li>The genre of text the pipeline is trained on</li>
        			<li>The size of the pipeline on disc. <tt>sm</tt> means small, <tt>md</tt> medium and <tt>lg</tt> large.
        			Besides the previously sizes there are also <tt>trf.sm</tt> and <tt>trf</tt> for transformer based models which tend to be large in general because they contain an entire deep learning model.</li>
        		</ol>
        		For more information also see the <a href="https://spacy.io/models#conventions">official spaCy documentation</a>.
        	</description>
        	<option name="Spacy Model Selection">
        		Select a model by selecting the corresponding line in the table.
        		You can sort the table by any of the columns by clicking on the column header.
        	</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Local model">
        	<description>
        		Allows to read a model from a file system.
        	</description>
    		<option name="Read from">
	        	The file system to read from.
	        	If no file system connection is connected to the node, you can choose from the local file system, a KNIME mountpoint or a relative location.
        	</option>
        	<option name="Folder">
        		The folder containing the pipeline you want to load.
        		Click the <i>Browse...</i> button to open a file browser.
        	</option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
		<outPort name="Spacy Model" index="0">The Spacy model</outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
