<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./ner.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.10" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10.xsd">
    <name>Spacy NER</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        The node assigns named entity tags to the words of the document.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        	The node assigns named entity tags to the words of the document.
        	<p>
        		Most models use the <tt>SPACY_NE</tt> tag set but some models might have additional tags.
        		In such a case a dynamic tag set is created for the model whose tag type is <tt>SPACY_NE_model</tt>
        		where <tt>model</tt> is the name of the model (as displayed in the Spacy Model Selector node) followed by its version.
        	</p>
			<p>
				Not all models provide this functionality.
				If a model doesn't provide it, a corresponding error is displayed upon configuration of the node.
			</p>
        </intro>
        <tab name="Options">
        	<option name="Select column">
        		Select a Document column that will be affected by NER tagging.
        	</option>
        	<option name="Replace column">
				If checked, the document column will be replaced by the new preprocessed documents.
				Otherwise the preprocessed documents will be appended as a new column.
        	</option>
        	<option name="Append column">
        		The name of the new appended column, containing the preprocessed documents.
        	</option>        	
        </tab>       
        <tab name="Python">
    		<option name="Python">
    			Select one of Python execution environment options:
    			<ul>
        			<li>use default Python environment for the Redfield NLP nodes</li>
        			<li>use Conda environment specified by a Conda flow variable (only selectable if such a flow variable is available)</li>
        		</ul>
    		</option>
        </tab>              
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
    	<inPort name="Spacy Model" index="0">The Spacy model</inPort>
		<inPort name="Input Table" index="1">The input table which contains the documents to preprocess.</inPort>
		<outPort name="Spacy Model" index="0">The Spacy model</outPort>
		<outPort name="Output Table" index="1">The output table which contains the preprocessed documents.</outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
